We sigh whenever we're about to come to a standstill
終わりなき旅の途中　立ち止まりそうな時
Owarinaki tabi no tochuu tachidomarisouna toki
While moving on this endless journey.
深いため息こぼす　僕らは
Fukai tameiki kobosu bokura wa
Everytime we lunge for it, it escapes and flies off.
掴みかけてはまた離れていった
Tsukamikaketewa mata hanareteitta
But now, there's nothing to be afraid of
でも今はもう何も恐れることはない
Demo ima wa mou nanimo osoreru koto wa nai
The powerful ties that bind our hearts
心を繋ぐ強い絆は
Kokoro wo tsunagu tsuyoi kizuna wa
Will never come loose.
けして解けはしないさ
Keshite hodoke wa shinai sa
After a lifetime of searching, we finally arrived
探し続けて辿り着いた
Sagashitsuzukete tadoritsuita
Here, where the period lies.
この場所で Period に
Kono basho de piriodo ni
Let's change all our sorrow and rage to power.
悲しみ怒り 力に変えて
Kanashimi ikari chikara ni kaete
Destiny is right within our reach.
運命はすぐそばに
Unmei wa sugu soba ni
来るべき約束の日
The forthcoming "Promised Day".
運命を決するその日に向け
People are continuing to prepare for the day that will determine their fate.
人々は準備を進めるのだった
Time passes by, and it is now spring.
そして  時は巡り頃は春
At last, the Promised Day is about to arrive.
いよいよ  約束の日が訪れる
Some sort of festival?
祭りかね
It's the Festival of the Sheep, a local specialty of Resembool that takes place every spring.
リゼンブール名物
春の羊祭ですよ
Sorry to ask something like this on an important day, but we'd like to replenish our water supplies.
そんな日にすまない
水の補給がしたいのだが
Sure thing.
いいですよ  いくらでもどうぞ
Have all the water you want.
Okay! Bring out the water tanks!
よ～し  タンク下ろせ
せぇ～の…
One, two...
There.
よいしょ
留守のようだな
Looks like there's no one home.
Here we are, miss.
着いたよ  お嬢ちゃん
Home sweet home.
うちのにおいだ
Wow, this place is full of automails.
機械鎧だらけだな
Please don't touch the ones that aren't finished yet.
作りかけは触らないでね
It's so dusty in here...
ほこりっぽいなぁ
What happened?!
どうした
ちょっ…
Edward Elric?!
エドワード·エルリック
Intruders?!
侵入者か
Oww!!
あ痛ぁ～
What the hell are you guys doing?
な～にやってんだ  お前ら
Lin?!
リン
痛て…
If I recall, you two are working for Kimblee!
貴様ら  確か  キンブリーの部下
Huh?
You guys are... from Briggs!
あれっ  お前ら  ブリッグズの
You chased us all the way down here?!
こんなとこまで追ってきたのか
Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait!
待て待て待て待て
銃を下ろせ
Put down your guns!
ちょっと  エド
Hey Ed... just what  is going on?
一体  何がどうなってるの
Long story.
話せば長いことなんだが…
だいたい  私の部屋で何してたのよ
Besides, what were you doing in my room?!
たまには外を見ながら
I just wanted to eat while enjoying the outside view every once in a while!
食べたかったんだよ
とにかく  銃を下ろせって
I said, put down your gun!
でかい声出すな
Quit yelling!
This dog is so loud.
犬  うるせぇなぁ
Get the hell out of my room!!
乙女の部屋から出てけ～
心配した
You had me worried sick.
I know.
Glad to see you're safe.
そっちこそ無事で…
A-Al isn't with you?
アルは一緒じゃないのか
Al's at the station!
エド  アルが駅にいるのよ
He's with Major Miles.
マイルズさんと一緒に
But they're about to depart soon.
すぐ出発しちゃうの
急げば  まだ間に合うかもしれない
If you hurry, you may be able to make it in time.
Something wrong?
どうしたの  行かないの
Aren't you going to go see him?
We're fugitives wanted by Central.
オレたちはセントラルのお尋ね者だ
誰かに見られたら  まずいんだ
It would be bad if someone were to see us.
だけど…
But...
The Festival of the Sheep, huh...
羊祭か…懐かしいな
Sure brings back memories.
We're going to be departing soon.
そろそろ出発だ
Roger.
はい
I hope you will have found your body by the next time you return to this town.
今度  帰ってくるときには
元の体に戻っているといいな
Thank you.
はい…
Winry?
ウィンリィ
おかえり
Welcome home.
Thanks.
ただいま  心配掛けて  ごめんね
Sorry for worrying you.
Looks like we have more of you dowdy people in here now.
むさ苦しいのが増えたねぇ
Sorry for causing such a ruckus earlier.
お騒がせして申し訳ありません
自分たちはブリッグズ兵であります
We're soldiers from Briggs.
We were dispatched as Miss Winry's bodyguards.
ウィンリィさんの護衛として
派遣されました
You're Lin... right?
リン…だよね
What?
You know this dude?
お前  こいつの知り合いか
The name's Greed.
グリードだ  よろしくな
Nice to meet ya.
Huh?
And so, these guys are currently working for me.
ってなわけで
今  こいつら  オレの手下
なんで ここに来たの
What made you come here?
To make sure his automail's all tuned up and stuff.
事に備えて
こいつの機械鎧の手入れとか
まっ  万全にしときたくてな
You know, to prepare for the worst.
Take a look at him later, Winry.
あとで見てやんな
You made all his latest stuff, so I can't do the fine-tuning.
お前が作った機械鎧だから
私には微調整できないんだよ
Sure, no problem.
分かった
Oh...
そっか
So the people of Lior have gotten back up on their feet again.
リオールは立ち直ってんのか
That's a relief.
よかった  気になってたんだ
It's been bugging me, to tell you the truth.
So, why is Al with Major Miles?
で  アルはなんだって
マイルズ少佐と一緒なんだ
I heard the people from Briggs are going to do something at the joint exercises in the east.
ブリッグズの人たち
東部の演習場で何かやるらしいの
アルはそれを手伝えるんじゃないかって
Al volunteered to join them, saying there might be something he could help out with.
自分から
Oh...
そっか
Your dad went to Central ahead of him.
エドのお父さんは
ひと足先にセントラルに行ったわ
I heard he's in some slum called 'Kanama', so you should meet up with him to get the details.
カナマっていうスラムにいるらしいから
会って  詳しい話を聞いてあげて
The Promised Day is coming up... right?
もうすぐ  約束の日なんでしょ
オレもグリードから聞いた
I heard about that from Greed as well.
It's a day when we may be able to get our bodies back,
or a day when a great tragedy will strike this nation.
元に戻れるチャンスでもあり
この国に大惨事が起こるかもしれない日だ
なあ
Hey...
Yeah?
何
ばっちゃんとデン連れて
Take Granny and Den and escape to another country.
外国に逃げとけ
Are you telling me to run away?!
逃げろって  何よ
身内だけ逃がして  どうすんの
Telling those close to you to escape makes it sound like you've already given up!
Can't you stop the threat to this country?!
あんたはこの国が
どうにかなっちゃうのを
止められないの
止めてやるよ
I'll stop them!
止めてやるけど
But there's a one in a million chance that it may not work!
万が一ってことがあんだろが
Be 100% sure, then!
万が一も億が一もない
あいつら  とんでもないこと
They're planning to do something terrible, aren't they?!
やろうとしてるんでしょ
Beat them to a pulp and protect our country!
そんなの  ぶっつぶして
この国守ってよ
And while you're at it, get your bodies back and return safe and sound!
そんで  エドもアルも
元の体に戻って帰ってきてよ
I'll do anything  to make that happen!
そのためなら私  なんでもするよ
Geez, you make it sound like a walk in the park.
ったく  簡単に言いやがってよ
What's this?!
何よ  弱気になるなんて
You're not acting like yourself-
あんたらしく…
Hey, Ed!
ちょっと  エド
Gosh, you're such an annoying woman.
ぎゃあぎゃあ  うるせぇ女だな
エド
Ed!
Fine woman you have up there.
いいねぇ  あの女
She just sounds like she wants everything
in the world. Quite the greedy one.
あれもこれもと  強欲で
When you get too greedy, it comes back to bite you in the behind.
強すぎる欲なんて
ろくなもんじゃねぇよ
See this?
見ろ  死んだ人間を欲したら
I wanted to bring back the dead, and this was my reward.
このざまだ
You really think so?
そうかい
"I long to see someone who died",
"I want to be rich", "I want women"...
「死んだヤツに会いたい」も
「金が欲しい」も
「女が欲しい」も
"I want to protect the world"...
「世界を守りたい」も
They're all desires.
全部  欲する心  すなわち願いだ
In other words, wishes.
If you ask me, there's neither 'right' nor 'wrong' when it comes to greed.
オレに言わせりゃあ
欲にいいも悪いもねぇ
You humans go around ranking certain types of greed in order from good to bad, which makes you so hard to understand.
欲っつうもんに偉そうに格付けするから
人間はややこしいんだよ
You're leaving now  of all times?
こんな時間に出かけるの
We were planning on leaving today anyway.
お前に会わなくても
今日出発するつもりだったんだ
Thanks for the tune-up.
機械鎧
整備してくれてありがとうよ
If you ever happen to see Hohenheim, deliver Trisha's message for her.
ホーエンハイムに会うことがあったら
トリシャの言葉伝えるんだよ
Sure, whatever.
へえへえ
Ed! I...
エド  私…
お前はちゃんと隠れてろよ
You stay hidden.
約束の日とやらに
I'll come home after putting an end to everything on the Promised Day, so...
全部終わらせて帰ってくっから
アップルパイでも焼いて待ってろ
...wait for us with a freshly-baked apple pie. Deal?
Deal!
Work today took forever.
今日もよく働いたな
でもよ  こんなことしてていいのか  オレたち
But hey, is this really what we should be focusing on right now?
もうすぐ約束の日だぞ
The Promised Day is coming up!
しょうがねぇだろ
Not much else we can do!
マルコーさんもスカーも
Doctor Marcoh and Scar haven't met up with us yet!
来ないんだから
Geez... where the hell are they?!
まったく
あの二人  どこで何を…
Doctor!
先生
Hey, it's you guys.
君たち
"Hey, it's you guys"?!
「おおっ 君たち」じゃないぜ
Where have you two been all this time?!
長いこと どこほっつき歩いてたんだよ
Sorry about that.
分かってる
Let's head over to Central.
セントラルに向かおう
But something feels a little off.
しかし  なんか妙な感じだよな
We used to be soldiers, but now we're working with an Ishbalan.
元軍人のオレたちが
イシュヴァール人と一緒に
行動するなんてよ
Yeah it does.
そうそう  オレたちにとっちゃあ
For us, Amestris is our birthplace.
アメストリスは
生まれた故郷だし  家族もいるし
We've got family here as well.
But Scar, who used to rebel against the nation, is now working to protect it.
でも  国に反逆してたスカーが
今こうして  この国を救うために
動いてるなんてなぁ
Don't get the wrong idea.
勘違いするな
My goal is not to protect this country.
この国を救うのではない
I'm working to change it.
変えるのだ
I'm working in order for the people of this country to recognize the existence of the Ishbalans,
イシュヴァールの民を否定したこの国に
a race that they denied.
我らの存在を認めさせるため
オレは動いている
In order to change the world,
you must start by changing yourself.
世界を変えるためには
まず  己が変わらねばならぬ
That's how it is, Amestrians.
そういうことだ
アメストリス人よ
Ishbalans?!
イシュヴァール人
Why?!
なんで…
We weren't just dawdling about for months doing nothing.
何か月も  ただ
ほっつき歩いてたわけじゃないのだよ
They're comrades who share our goal.
志を共にする仲間たちだ
May this year's exercises be productive as always, Lieutenant General.
今年もよろしくお願いします  閣下
I'm glad we're doing it in the east this year.
いや～今回の演習がこっちで助かったよ
Joint exercises in the north are pretty tough for us.
北での合同演習はしんどいからねぇ
準備は整っとるよ
Everything's ready on our end.
Ours, too.
こちらも手はずはすでに
Unfortunately, a little problem has popped up...
しかし  ちと厄介なことになってなぁ
That being?
厄介なこと
Little miss Bradley is here to observe as well.
なんと  ブラッドレイちゃんが
見物に来てんだよねぇ
なっ
I was expecting someone high up to watch over the practice, since it's right before the Promised Day...
約束の日が目前ですから
演習の監視役は
それなりの人間とは覚悟してましたが…
We'll just have to figure something out.
まっ  なんとかするしかないねぇ
There it is again...
まただ
The delay between visions is gradually getting shorter.
あっちに引っ張られる間隔が
だんだん短くなってる
急がなきゃ
I have to hurry.
I need to get my body back, or...
早く元の体に戻らないと…
Yeah, I can smell him!
におう  におうよ
鋼の錬金術師の弟のにおいだ
Smells like the Fullmetal Alchemist's little brother!
Running away?
逃げるの
まずい
This isn't good!
こんな状態じゃ  まともに戦えない
I'm in no condition to fight!
What's... this...?!
なんだ…これ…
Talk about great timing...!
こんなときに…また…
I'm going to have you keep quiet until the Promised Day,
約束の日まで
おとなしくしていてもらいますよ
Alphonse Elric.
アルフォンス·エルリック
どうも  少将閣下
Good evening, Major General.
貴様なぞに出す茶はないぞ
I've got no tea for the likes of you.
近々  食事にお誘いできるかもしれません
I may be able to take you out for dinner soon.
いつぞやの約束を果たす気になったか
So you finally plan to fulfill the promise from forever ago?
それにしても広い屋敷ですね
'Large' doesn't even begin to describe this mansion.
The wealth of the Armstrong family never ceases to amaze me.
さすがアームストロング家
中隊…
You could fit a company... no, even a full battalion in here.
いや  大隊くらいは入りそうだ
私にもしものことがあったら
If something may happen to me,
この屋敷
you can have the entire mansion.
丸ごとくれてやってもいいぞ
棺おけに屋敷は入らんからな
It won't fit into my coffin, after all.
弟君には譲らないのですか
You're not going to give it to your brother?
あいつにやるくらいなら
I'd say you're the better choice... by a hair.
貴様の方がまだ  毛一本ほどマシだ
それは光栄です
That's quite an honor.
遅ればせながら
Belatedly...
アームストロング家当主になられた
This is to congratulate you for becoming the head of the Armstrong family.
お祝いです
ヒヤシンス…
Hyacinths...?
セリム·ブラッドレイは人造人間
"Selim Bradley is a Homunculus."
ご存じですか
Are you aware of what the Hyacinth represents?
ヒヤシンスの花言葉
知らん
I'm not.
「しとやかな  かわいらしさ」
Feminine beauty.
余計なお世話だ
I don't need your flowers!
それではこれにて  閣下
Well, if you'll excuse me, Major General.
青二才めが
You amateur.
One Day Prior to the "Promised Day"
うざったいなぁ
This is annoying.
どさくさに紛れて
We should just aim a cannon at Bradley's tower and be done with it.
大砲でブラッドレイのいるとこを
吹き飛ばしちゃおうか
やめてください
Please don't.
マイルズ少佐
Major Miles.
アルフォンス·エルリックの
So we still don't have a clue as to where Alphonse Elric disappeared to...
所在はまだつかめないか…
Yes. We're still searching, but...
捜索は続けているのですが…
Could it be that he was captured?
まさか  向こうに捕まったのでしょうか
明日は約束の日だというのに…
And the Promised Day is tomorrow...
閣下
Sire.
ハクロ少将です
Major General Hakuro has arrived.
閣下  グラマン中将のことで
Sire, there's something I need to inform you about Lieutenant General Grumman-
お伝えしたいことが…
東方軍を使って  クーデターか
A coup d'etat using the Eastern army?
だとしたら  予想の範囲内だ
We've already planned for such eventualities.
いえ
No, the joint practice is a bait.
東と北の合同演習はおとりです
閣下が東にいることにより
The Ishbalan remnants will commit a terrorist act in Central,
手薄になったセントラルで
イシュヴァールの残党がテロを行います
now that defenses have weakened since Your Highness is here in the east.
そして  グラマン中将は
Lieutenant General Grumman will use "terrorist suppression" as a pretense to invade Central.
テロ鎮圧を口実に
セントラルに侵攻
マスタング大佐と呼応し
He's planning on taking advantage of the confusion to take over Central Headquarters,
混乱に乗じて
中央司令部を乗っ取る計画です
with the help of Colonel Mustang.
ハクロ少将の情報どおり
Just as Major General Hakuro stated,
ここ数日で多数のイシュヴァール人が
many Ishbalans have infiltrated Central vicinity over the past few days.
セントラル付近に潜入したとのことです
私はセントラルに戻る
I'm returning to Central.
あとは任せたぞ
I'll leave matters here in your hands.
はっ
Roger.
That damned Mustang... planning something outrageous.
マスタングめ  大それたことを…
使える手駒を引き離して
I thought we took care of him when we
separated him from all of his useful men...
牙は抜いたというのに
止まったぞ
The train stopped.
どうしたんだ
What's going on?
羊だ
Sheep crossing.
急いでいるというのに…
Dammit, we're in a rush for time...!
Hey, they just left us!
機関車だけが動きだしたぞ
何ぃ
What?!
どうなってる  おい  止めさせろ
What's going on?!
Hey! Make him stop!
線路上の羊は排除しました
The sheep on the tracks have been exterminated.
予定どおり
We'll be heading to Central as planned.
セントラルに向かいます
行くぞ  大佐がお待ちかねだ
Let's go!
The Colonel is awaiting our arrival.
はっ
Yes, sir!
くそっ
Dammit!
まんまと利用されましたな
You played right into their hands, Major General Hakuro.
ハクロ少将
閣下の乗った列車が
The train that was carrying the Führer President has been bombed!
爆破されましたぞ
なっ
What?!
明日  すべてが動きだす
Everything begins tomorrow.
やるべきことをやるわよ
Time to make our move,
ブレダ少尉  フュリー曹長
Second Lieutenant Breda, Master Sergeant Fuery.
「少尉」は勘弁してください
No need for the "Second Lieutenant", ma'am.
今はただの脱走兵ですよ
We're just plain old deserters now.
お先  真っ暗だ
There goes my future...
全部  終わったら
We'll have the Colonel take responsibility after everything's over.
大佐に責任取ってもらいましょ
The promise we never made
交わしたはずのない約束が
Kawashita hazu no nai yakasoku ga
yet again
今日も
Kyou mo
tries to snatch our future away from us.
僕らの未来を奪おうとする
Bokura no mirai wo ubaou to suru
Why is it that we can't rejoice
欲しがっていたものを手にしても
Hoshigatteita mono wo te ni shitemo
straight from the heart
素直に
Sunao ni
when we obtain something we've always been after?
うまく笑えないのはなぜだろう
Umaku waraenai nowa nazedarou
The overflowing tears aren't from feebleness or remorse.
あふれる涙は　弱さや後悔じゃない
Afureru namida wo yowasa ya koukai ja nai
They're fragments born from agony.
イタミが生んだカケラで
Itami ga unda kakera de
Of all the moments and destinies,
どんな瞬間だって運命だって
Donna shunkan datte unmei datte
I realized there's one absolute certainty.
ひとつだけ確かなものがあると知った
Hitotsu dake tashika na mono ga aru to shitta
Even if things get tough and I'm at my limit
限界だって困難だって
Genkai datte konnan datte
I refuse to give up.
あきらめたくないよ
Akirametakunaiyo
Please, don't let go.
このまま離さないで
Konomama hanasanaide
I can feel the warmth of your right hand
かたく握りしめた　君の右手のぬくもり
Kataku nigirishimeta kimi no migite no nukumori
where it's tightly joined with my left.
ここにあるから
Koko ni arukara
大総統が
The Führer President?!
キング·ブラッドレイが死ぬなど…
There's no way King Bradley could die...!
まだ  そうと決まったわけではなかろう
We can't make assumptions just yet!
捜索はどうなっておる
What has the investigation turned up?!
まだ  現場に部隊が…
The squadron has yet to reach the scene of the accident!
頭がいなくなった途端  これだ
As soon as their leader is gone, this happens.
Make them hurry up!
Quit yelling!
PLACEHOLDER
This is not my job!
しょせんは烏合の衆
In the end, they're nothing but an undisciplined mob.
But...!
This isn't the time for this!
そんなことを言ってる場合か
最高司令官が不在なのだぞ
The supreme commander is missing!
PLACEHOLDER
分かっておるわ
I know that!
動くチャンスか…
This may be my chance...
このような所に
I never expected someone as important as you to visit this place.
おいでになられるとは
皆  落ち着け
Calm down, everyone.
セントラルには私がいる
I'm still here.
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
暗闇に潜むは
What lurks in the shadows?
魔物か  獣か  化け物か
Demons? Beasts? Monsters?
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
危機に陥る少年たちを
A black gust of wind saves our heroes who are faced with a crisis.
救うは黒き一陣の風
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Fullmetal  Alchemist
第４７話　『闇の使者』
Episode 47, Emissary of Darkness.
光を当てろ
Shed light on the heart of man. To an engulfing darkness.
人の心に深い闇に